Daniel Hengeveld

Amsterdam, Netherlands +31 627882813 danielwh@gmail.com

I'm a 20 year veteran of the software industry and love to build things, both through leadership and direct contribution. My goal is to help a group of people learn and grow while working on something worthwhile. This can involve coding, coaching, leading, or architecting. I have a "humans first" philosophy toward building software and enjoy the dual challenge of solving hard problems and building great teams.

SKILLS

- Engineering leadership mentoring and managing, org design
- Hiring / team building
- Software engineering in JS / TS / ReactJS / Ruby / Rails / Python
- Architecture / systems design
- Product research & development
- Remote team coordination
- Guiding legacy teams/products in adopting modern development processes/tools

EXPERIENCE

Principal Engineer / Platform Architect MURAL - 2021-2023

Visual collaboration tool

- Defined cross-department technical strategy with leadership team
- Worked in Platform to ensure scalability during growth in staff and user base
- Served as architect and most senior IC for the 90-person Platform department, focusing on the technical roadmap and coordinating all teams in the department
- Responsible for technical correctness of 7 teams, through mentoring and designing with the 7 staff engineers of those teams.
- Contributed directly to all areas of public API project
- Researched, built prototypes, and planned cross-team engineering projects
- Provided mentoring and technical leadership to engineers at all levels
- Contributed to product and org design efforts during reorganization
- Part of department leadership team, along with Sr. Directors of Engineering,
 Product, and Design

Head of Engineering, Stitch (PVH Europe) - 2018-2021

3D apparel design & asset management tools, innovation team for major apparel company

• Built cross-functional team from zero

- Set engineering standards and platform roadmap
- Led & participated in development of critical services & features
- Set vision & priorities as part of the Stitch leadership team
- Directed architecture & technology choices
- Managed 3 teams of 15 total engineers

Senior Software Engineer, GitHub 2012-2016

Industry standard collaborative software development platform

- Member of the Atom editor team
- Planned and built the atom.io site and package management API including deployment and operation
- Maintained and built several internal tools
- Contributed to Atom community management and open source maintainership

Technical Cofounder, Favortree / NeighborGoods 2012

Time bank and community goods exchange

- Joined as 'technical cofounder' during fundraising / prototyping phase of new product.
- Built prototype single-page app
- Assisted in fundraising and user research

Senior Product Engineer, Border Stylo 2010-2012

Web annotation tool "Glass"

- Collaborated on large modular Javascript application with multiple build targets (browser extensions, web application, mobile)
- Designed and implemented general-purpose business metrics system
- Maintained Ruby + MySQL API backend

Software Engineer, DigiSynd/Disney 2009-2010

Social media campaign performance tracking / sentiment analysis

- Web services development in Python
- User activity and sentiment data gathering and analysis with Cassandra, Hadoop and Pig

Software Engineer, Revver 2009-2010

Video sharing service

- Ported large-scale Ruby/Rails app to Python/Django with feature enhancements, maintained both
- Maintained Twisted Python-based XML-RPC API

EDUCATION

Calvin College — Interdisciplinary with electives in computer science, film, and communications, 2000-2004